A Guide to the James Branch Cabell Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #5947-h
James Branch Cabell Collection 1916-1946, n.d.
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
5947-h
ca. 125 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit, 1964 March 24
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1916 Nov 16; ALS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [after 1921]; ALS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1924 Jun 7; ALS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1926 Sep 28; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1927]; ALS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1927]; ALS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1927]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1929 Jul 30; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1929 Sep 20; ALS, 4 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1929 Dec 18; ALS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1929]; ALS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1929]; ALS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1929]; ALS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1931]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1931]; ALS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1932]; ALS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1933]; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1934 Sep 30; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, with 2 pp. ALS, 1934 Jan 15, Anna Elgstrom to Glasgow, TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1934]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1934]; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1934]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1935 Jul 22; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1935 Jul 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1935 Aug 17; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1935 Aug 23; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1935 Oct 23; ALS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Mrs. James Branch Cabell, 1936 Feb 13; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1936]; ALS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1936]; ALS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1937 Mar 19; TLS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Mr. and Mrs. James Branch Cabell, [1937] May 24; APCS
  - Ellen Glasgow to Mr. and Mrs. James Branch Cabell, [1937]; ALS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1937]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1937]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1937]; ALS, 4 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1937]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1937]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1937]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1937]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1937]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to [ James Branch Cabell], [1937]; ANS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1938 Feb 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1938] Apr 14; ALS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1938] Apr 15; AL, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1938] May 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Mrs. James Branch Cabell, 1938 May 30; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1938 Jul 6; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1938 Jul 28; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1938 Aug 10; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1938]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1938]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1938]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1938]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1938]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1938]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1938]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1938]; ALS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1938]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1939 Oct 5; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1939 Nov 24; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1940 Jan 7; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1940 Jan 16; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1940 Jan 25; TLS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1940 Jan 29; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1940 Feb 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1940 May 2; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1940 Jul 20; ALS, 3 p.
  - Grace D. Vanamee to Ellen Glasgow, w/AN at bottom, Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1940 Sep 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1940 Sep 14; TLS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1940]; ALS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1941 Jan 15; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1941 Feb 25; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1941] Apr 8; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1941 Apr 14]; Birthday card
  - Ellen Glasgow to Mrs. James Branch Cabell, 1941 May 26; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1941 Jun 6; ALS, 4 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1941 Aug 1; TLS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1941 Aug 30; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1941 Sep 3; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1941 Sep 14; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1941 Oct 31; ALS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to Mrs. James Branch Cabell, 1941 Dec 30; ALS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1942 Jan 9; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1942 Jan 24; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1942 Jun 27; TL, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1942 Aug 7; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1942]; ALS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1942]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1942]; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1943 Jan 30; TLS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1943 Jun 25; TLS, 4 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1943 Jul 29; TLS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, 1943 Sep 7; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1943] Sep 10; TNS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1943] Oct 28; TLS, 2 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, [1943]; TLS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, n.d.; ALS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, n.d.; TLS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, n.d.; ALS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, n.d.; ALS, 3 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, n.d.; ALS, 1 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, n.d.; ALS, 4 p.
  - Ellen Glasgow to James Branch Cabell, n.d.; ALS, 2 p.
- Miscellaneous
  - List of possible titles for Beyond Defeat, marked "Confidential", TMs
  - Notes about Barren Ground, AMs
  - About death of Ellen Ellen Glasgow, 1945 Nov 22; 10 clippings
  - "An Exchange of Letters Between Ellen Glasgow and Marjorie Kinnan Rawlings, " from Atlanta Journal, 1946 Apr 28; Clipping